<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | 传鹏的实验室</title>
    <link>https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/zh/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/zh/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>zh-Hans</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/media/icon_hu3a6db96f210420c7d44d3ddf0142fcf7_129407_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/zh/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most data are available upon request: A case report</title>
      <link>https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/zh/post/post_230520/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/zh/post/post_230520/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is written by Mengzhen Hu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Open data is a growing trend among academic journals. Authors can either posit their data on an open repository or leave a statement “Data is available upon (reasonable) request”. Recently, a few papers checked whether “Data is available upon request”. A recent preprint in social psychology, among other published studies, depicted a quit bleak picture that “Data is not available upon request” (Gabelica et al., 2022; Hussey, 2023; Tedersoo et al., 2021).
To add some anecdote data to the topic about “Data available upon request” statement, we also share our experience in request data here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;background&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am involved in two ongoing and interconnected projects. The first project focuses on conducting a meta-analysis of articles that have employed the Self-perceptual matching task (SPMT) paradigm. The second project aims to assess the reliability of the SPMT paradigm by reanalyzing research data in published studies. To strengthen the persuasiveness of our findings, the second project requires us to search for publicly available data within the database established from the first project (see our preregistration: &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/zv628&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://osf.io/zv628&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;more-datasets-are-available-after-2018&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More datasets are available after 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our meta-analysis database covers a total of 136 articles citing Sui et al. (2012) from 2013 to 2021 (it should be noted that articles from 2021 may not be included in the database). Among these 136 articles, only 27 claim to have publicly available data. Within these 27 articles, 21 directly provide original data through links in their papers. However, out of these 21 articles, one of them includes an OSF address in their paper, yet it does not contain any data. Furthermore, the remaining 6 articles mention that “Data is available upon request.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;230520_fig1.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
Figure 1. Number of Paper with or without open data
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;more-open-data-than-upon-request&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More open data than “upon request”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our reliability project, we selected articles that are only slightly deviated from the original paradigm. That said, we need to get access to data from 14 articles (see our preregistration for details).
Among these articles, 9 of them provided links in papers. One of the nine links was empty. We reached out to authors via email, so far, no changes on OSF page.
The remaining 5 articles stated that “Data is available upon request”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;230520_fig2.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
Figure 2. Data is already public or upon request
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;of-data-are-available-upon-request&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;60% of data are available upon request&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those 5 papers, we sent emails and received responses from each author. Among them, three authors (60%) directly provided trial-level data, allowing us to use this data for our purpose. Additionally, two authors provided average values of participants under different experimental conditions.
In a sense, all the articles claiming ‘Data is available upon request’ have provided us with data, though not all data are useful for our purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;230520_fig3.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
Figure 3. Feedback Data After Request
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the process of requesting data from original authors was relatively smooth, with the majority of authors responding promptly and being willing to share their data. Although two authors provided only individuals’ summary data due to various reasons, these data might be of use for meta-analysis.
In our experience, most of authors have a positive attitude towards data sharing and are willing to respond to our requests. However, not all trial-level data are available, as some authors may encounter technical issues or lack of time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
As an early career researcher who request data for the first time, I have learned three lessons. (1), write the emails well. I refer the article published in Science (Gruber et al., 2020) on how to write emails. (2), provide as much information about why you need the data as possible. In our case, our protocol and code are already open on GitHub (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Chuan-Peng-Lab/ReliabilitySPE&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Chuan-Peng-Lab/ReliabilitySPE&lt;/a&gt;), and we included it in all our emails. (3), update the authors’ email through searching. As mentioned by Hussey (2023) in their article, the email addresses provided in many papers may be incorrect and unable to reach the authors. We searched for authors’ information on Google Scholar and found their latest publications and obtain their currently used email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;reference&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gabelica, M., et al. (2022). Many researchers were not compliant with their published data sharing statement: a mixed-methods study. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 150, 33-41. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2022.05.019&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2022.05.019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gruber, J., et al. (2020). A scientist’s guide to email etiquette. Science. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.caredit.abb2664&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.caredit.abb2664&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hussey, I. (2023). Data is not available upon request. &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyarxiv.com/jbu9r/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://psyarxiv.com/jbu9r/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sui, J., et al. (2012). Perceptual effects of social salience: Evidence from self-prioritization effects on perceptual matching. Journal of experimental psychology. Human perception and performance, 38(5), 1105-1117. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/a0029792&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/a0029792&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tedersoo, L., et al. (2021). Data sharing practices and data availability upon request differ across scientific disciplines. Scientific data, 8(1), 192. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-021-00981-0&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-021-00981-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install and use HDDM</title>
      <link>https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/zh/post/2019-04-29-how-to-install-and-use-hddm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 02:13:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://chuan-peng-lab.netlify.app/zh/post/2019-04-29-how-to-install-and-use-hddm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feburary 14, 2021 update: Please note that this blog post was outdated because of the updates of Anaconda/miniconda.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;August 2020 update: I&amp;rsquo;ve created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/hcp4715/hddm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HDDM docker image&lt;/a&gt;, which can be easily installed and used after installing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;docker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HDDM is a python package for drift diffusion model (DDM, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://ski.clps.brown.edu/hddm_docs/%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://ski.clps.brown.edu/hddm_docs/)&lt;/a&gt;. I used it to decompose the reaction time and accuracy data in my recent manuscript: &lt;a rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; aria-label=&#34;Good Me Bad Me: Does Valence Influence Self-Prioritization During Perceptual Decision-Making (opens in a new tab)&#34; href=&#34;https://psyarxiv.com/9fczh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Good Me Bad Me: Does Valence Influence Self-Prioritization During Perceptual Decision-Making&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few tips on how to install and use HDDM, in case that you plan to replicate my analyses using the code and data I share &lt;a rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34; aria-label=&#34;here on Github (opens in a new tab)&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/hcp4715/moralSelf_ddm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The targeted reader of this post are Windows users. (I assume that for most Linux users, you, in the most cases, can figure out how to install and use this package, at least with the help from the online forum (&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/hddm-users%29%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/hddm-users))&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My system information: Win 10 pro, 64 bit, 16 GB RAM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-prepare-the-python-environment&#34;&gt;Step 1: prepare the python environment:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.1. Download and install Anaconda 3.6 or 3.7 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.2. Create virtue python 3.5 environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do that, you need first run the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anaconda Prompt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which will be available after you installed Anaconda, as administrator, then run the following code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;conda create -vv -n py35 python=3.5 jupyter  # py35 is the name of the environment, which can be arbitrary &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.3. Activate the py35 env. :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# To activate this environment, use:

conda activate py35

# To deactivate an active environment, use:
conda deactivate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-install-hddm&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: install HDDM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you have a python 3.5 environment, you can then install the HDDM package. Of course, you need to activate the py35 environment first. Then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.1. Install HDDM by following code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;conda install -c pymc hddm  # (or conda install -c pymc python=3.5 hddm )
-proceed?: y&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.2. Update kabuki, which is crucial package that HDDM depends on, to 0.6.2, otherwise models can not be saved). You can check the version of kabuki to make sure you do have installed 0.6.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install -U --no-deps kabuki --ignore-installed

conda list # check the version of kabuki &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-use-hddm&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3: use HDDM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we almost ready. A final step is to use an appropriate editor for editing and running the scripts. I used both jupyter lab (an updated version of jupyter notebook, but you can use jupyter notebook) and spyder. The script files of the former ends with “.ipynb”, the script files of the later one end with “.py”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use jupyter lab, if you like, you need to install jupyter lab in your py35 env. As follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
conda install jupyter lab
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, changing the working directory of &lt;em&gt;anaconda prompt&lt;/em&gt; to the folder where you stored the scripts and data, and type &lt;em&gt;jupyter lab&lt;/em&gt; to open run jupyter lab. Note the (weird) way to change directory in windows system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
cd /d c:\goodme\2_pilot_study\Results\4_hddm\  # in windows you have to add /d to change the directory

# run in jupyter lab or jupyter note book, for stim-based modelling

jupyter lab #(or jupyter notebook if you use jupyter notebook)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, to run in spyder, you need to install spyder in this py35 env. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;conda install spyder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, type &lt;em&gt;spyder&lt;/em&gt; to activate spyder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;wp-block-code&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;spyder # you will need to change the working directory in the script.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final note&lt;/strong&gt;: I know that there exists &lt;em&gt;the curse of knowledge&lt;/em&gt;, which means that I may assume you know what I know but you don’t. So please free feel to post comment or shout out on twitter (@hcp4715) to let me know if you encountered any problem when reproducing my analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
